ARAF AL-JAMI

arafaljami1331@gmail.com \diamond araf.aljami.me \diamond +8801755045141

SUMMARY

Around 1 years of working experience as a software engineer, with a strong pursuit of problem solving. Hands on experience in building enterprise applications and maintaining best practices with OOD. Followed SOLID principles and design patterns to write clean, maintainable and adaptive code.

SKILLS

Languages: C/C++, Javascript, Typescript, C#

Specialties: .NET, .NET Core, Web API, GraphQL, Git, Agile Scrum methodology, Angular, AngularJS.

Database and messaging: MongoDB, MySQL, RabbitMQ.

EXPERIENCE

SELISE rockin' software, Dhaka

Nov 2018 - Present

Software Engineer

- · Developed Single Page Web Application using Angular, AngularJS
- · Developed REST API using C#/ASP.NET Core, RabbitMQ, MongoDB

Problem Setter and Judge at LU CSE Carnival IUPC 2019

· Set problem and written alternate solution. [link]

Problem Setter and Judge at NSU Cybernauts National Programming Contest 2019

· Set problem and written alternate solution. [link]

Programming Workshop Coordinator

March 2018 - December 2018

Leading University, Sylhet

· Arranged and taken workshop on programming and problem solving.

EDUCATION

Leading University, Sylhet

September 2014 - April 2019

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Onsite Competitive Programming Contests

September 2014 - Present

- \cdot 10th place (4th place University wise) out of **150** teams, at IUBAT ACM NCPC 2018. [link]
- · 16th place (8th place University wise) out of **120** teams, at MIST IUPC 2019

Online Competitive Programming Contests

September 2014 - Present

- · Active participant in online coding challenges on sites such as **TopCoder**, **Codeforces**.
- · Achieved Maximum Rating of 1982 (top 4%) in Codeforces. Handle: CLown1331. [link]
- · Achieved Maximum Rating of 1469 (Division 1) in TopCoder. Handle: CLown1331. [link]
- · Solved around 2500 problems in various online judges. [link]

PROJECTS

PROJECT RENEGADE [link]

- · Developed Using C# and Unity Game engine.
- · Designed and implemented all the game play element and systems.